Tomorrow’s Agriculture
Yomogi Preschool
People on 2nd Block
People on 6th Block
12 eyecatch}
Yoshimura Keita
Feel free to take one.
Yoshimura
Next Episode
"…The Concealed Prayer."
What’s… with that outfit?
We’re digging up potatoes at the preschool today!
Where and how did you see it done like that?!
In a magazine at the convenience store.
Everyone was dressed like this while working in the fields.
How the hell are you supposed to
dig potatoes with a butterfly net?!
Thank you for everything this year as well.
You’re welcome.
Take as many as you like.
Thank you so much.
Got it? You’re responsible for
carrying any potatoes you dig up.
Dig up only as many as you can carry, promise?
Kobato-chan, look! They’re connected!
They’re so big!
They really are!
It’s like looking for treasure!
Ow…
That’s huge!
Amazing!
D-Dobato…
Kobato-chan, your butt’s covered in dirt.
Huh?
Who’s that?
He looks a little older than the
children from Yomogi Preschool.
Is he a member of this house?
No, the grandchild of this
family is already in high school.
Then…
Whose child is he?
Hey.
Are you alone?
Do you live in the neighborhood?
Wait!
I’m sorry, it took us a while to realize.
Oh, there are those who cause mischief sometimes.
I wonder if he lives in the neighborhood…
All right, we should wrap this up and get going soon.
Okay!
You sure dug up a lot!
Kobato-chan!
That’s a lot of potatoes.
I worked hard!
Hey.
As I said when we started…
…you’re responsible for carrying what you dig up.
Now, let’s go back and grill them.
Kobato-chan, will you be okay?
Should we carry some for you?
I’ll be fine! I can carry them by myself!
All of them would be too much.
I’ll help.
No, we promised that we
would carry what we dug up!
Of course.
You really are a bully…
Th-This is impossible. Give it up, Kobato.
Miss.
We’ll help.
Really?
Thank you.
Are they ready yet?
It’s smoky!
Is it hot?
Here.
Thanks!
They’re hot, so be careful!
Hey!
Here.
Yum.
What should we do with all of these?
Should I grill some more?
Let’s give them to the neighbors.
Fujimoto-kun, would you go with Kobato-chan?
I can go by myself.
It’ll be faster that way.
But I still think she should go.
I want her to get to know the neighbors more too.
Is that okay, Kobato-chan?
Yes!
I will do my best!
I won’t ask for your help.
Don’t get in my way.
My potatoes!
He really is a bully. He keeps
telling me not to get in his way.
He didn’t say “don’t come with me,” though.
But he took my potatoes.
I was thinking of handing them out.
Maybe he took them because he
thought they were too heavy for you.
Yes?
We’re from Yomogi Preschool.
We picked some delicious potatoes,
and we’d like to share some with you!
Oh, my. Thank you!
We’re from Yomogi Preschool!
Oh, thank you!
They’re potatoes!
Thank you.
We’re from Yomogi Preschool!
Fujimoto-san!
We’ll be finished giving out the potatoes soon!
Yeah.
My, my.
Welcome back.
Hello!
Oh, my.
Young miss, it’s been a while.
Yes!
Milk, are you doing well?
You’ve gotten a little bigger.
That’s right.
It’s doing fine.
That’s…
Oh, he passed by and asked if he could use some water.
He said he dug up some potatoes.
You’re… the kid from earlier!
Take this!
Wait!
I told you to wait!
Let go, you thief!
That’s my line!
Potato thief.
Let me go!
Fujimoto-san, what are you doing?
I’m taking this thief to the police.
No!
I’ll give them back! I’ll give them back!
I knew it.
You’re a runaway.
Runaway?
What’s your name?
Now you won’t say anything?
“Potato Thief” will do.
I’m not a potato thief!
You have a name, don’t you?
Keita.
Why did you run away from home?
I wanted to go to my old home.
Your old home?
I had to move out of the house I lived in because Mom’s company changed.
So what happened to your old home?
I haven’t been there yet.
Were you on the way?
I was trying to go there, but…
You forgot where it was.
I didn’t forget!
No, that face says you forgot it.
No!
You wouldn’t forget where your home was, right?
I mean… I was still in kindergarten when I moved…
I got a little lost…
That means you forgot it.
I haven’t forgotten!
Keita-kun.
If you know what house it is,
we might be able to help you find it.
Can you draw what your house looks like?
Yeah, I can!
Let’s see, um…
The roof was red, and there was a window here…
Here was the antenna, and…
Draw what’s around your house too.
It’ll be easier to find that way.
There was a mailbox here, a dog nearby…
That’s a big dog.
He always barks whenever I pass by.
And then, and then…
Mom always baked sweets…
She read picture books to me,
and she’d take me to camps and
amusement parks during her breaks…
Keita-kun?
I want to go back to my old home.
Fujimoto-san.
I’d like to help Keita-kun find his home.
We won’t be able to find it with
just a dog and a mailbox as clues.
Do you remember anything else?
Which way? Right, left?
Um… th-this way…
Maybe it was this way.
I know this place! I’ve been here!
Really? We might be close.
Keita-kun, isn’t that great?
Yeah!
Want a drink?
I’ll be fine. I should economize.
Economize?
You know some difficult words.
Mom said it a lot.
Over here.
Fujimoto-san?
That’s…
It is what it looks like.
Here.
Really?
Let’s leave these in return.
Delicious!
They’re good.
Fujimoto does have some good sides.
Well… if he didn’t, that’d be troublesome.
Give me a pear too!
Yummy!
Could that dog be…?
So that means…
This house next door…
This isn’t my house.
We’re going in.
I’m opening it.
My room.
It’s locked.
We’ll have to bust in.
Fujimoto-san!
Please…
Don’t break it!
You don’t want to go back to the house you live in now?
But my grandpa’s there.
Your grandfather?
Yeah.
Mom and I are living with my grandpa now.
Keita-kun, do you not like your grandfather?
He’s such a bully!
Bully…
I mean…
He’s so noisy when he wakes me up in the morning.
Hey, Keita! Wake up already!
Hurry up and clean up!
I want to watch more TV at
night and play video games…
Keita!
Grandpa, what’re you doing?!
Stop staying up late and get to bed already!
He keeps telling me to eat all
the things I hate during dinner.
The things you hate?
Like the small fish and vegetables.
Keita!
Don’t play with your food! Eat it!
Is that bullying?
It is! Grandpa hates me!
That’s why he says all those mean things to me and thinks I should just leave!
That’s why that house…
Keita-kun.
Sayaka-sensei tells the kids in the preschool
to eat their fish and vegetables because they have nutrients.
Who’s Sayaka-sensei?
Sayaka-sensei is the kind teacher at
Yomogi Preschool who loves children.
Kind?
Keita!
Once you’ve finished your bath, head to bed!
It’s hard to tell when someone’s bullying you or not.
But if you take a careful look, you might figure it out.
Keita, were you…
…going to grill potatoes here or something?
It was really nice when we
grilled potatoes here last time.
You should take responsibility and return some.
I’ve already apologized to the farmer lady.
She’s the one who dug up too many, and now we’ve got a lot leftover.
Keita-kun, isn’t that great?
Yeah.
Are you sure you can go back by yourself?
I’ll be fine!
Keita!
Grandpa…
Go on.
Grandpa!
Keita…
Keita!
Ow!
What was that for, you old fart?
Don’t make people worry, you complete idiot!
Come on, let’s go home!
Yeah.
Mom’s waiting too.
Keita-kun’s with his grandfather and they’re about to get on the train.
Oh, no problem. Bye.
Fujimoto-san, were you calling Keita-kun’s home?
Did you call Keita-kun’s grandfather to come?
Who knows.
Besides that, I’m hungry.
When we get back, maybe I’ll eat some steamed potatoes.
Um…
Okay.
What?
Nothing.
Good evening.
Doumoto-san!
Are you heading home now?
I’ve got things to do, so I’ll leave first.
Things to do?
We dug up potatoes at the preschool today.
And we’ve been giving them to the neighbors.
Oh.
Fujimoto-san…
He really is a good person.
Yeah. Kiyokazu is a good guy.
That must be the kid’s.
Keita-kun seemed sad about his old house though.
Well, it must be because he understands how his grandfather really feels now.
I see.
Now then, since Fujimoto did so much work today…
Half score of 50 points!
But… Fujimoto-san was such a bully in the morning.
That’s true…
Then I’ll cancel that out and Fujimoto gets zero.
I’ll give a 70 for your work!
Erase the other one before you write that!
You’re so full of complaints!
Then let's bring it back to 50 points!
After you erase it…!
Shut up!
25 points!
Still unsatisfied?!
Then 12.5 points!
My face is pitch black!